hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft
whoa that was that was really good
timing and we are starting off today's
episode in hermitland where something um
well just just a bit of a coincidence
really a bit a bit unfortunate a bit of
a coincidence but basically you'll see
that there's a few games been added over
here here here and here and this is
actually all one game this game is by
exumavoid or xio zuma voyage and
unfortunately
the hive mind is real because he's made
the floor is lava
which is exactly what i was making over
here
with the the giant haunted mansion that
i talked about last episode as you can
see i have actually started this project
and i've got well most of the body done
there's still a long way to go but
here's a little time lapse of me making
this part of the build
so i'm gonna speed this up triple times
seeing as you know exactly what this is
going to look like and indeed the full
thing will look like the exact haunted
mansion that i made a couple of years
ago but i'm hoping that we can also make
it just a tiny bit different as well
so it's a bit unfortunate but the thing
is x's game is actually significantly
different or at least it's not finished
so i'm guessing but it is significantly
different to my game his seems to be a
redstone based timer where you've got to
walk through it and get to checkpoints
and stuff whereas mine is going to be
more of a parkour and collection and
exploration game
so
same premise different game so i think
i'm gonna plow on with this one anyway
and see if i can get it done well at
least the building will be done i think
i'm not gonna have enough time to
actually make the mini game on the
inside with all the lava we're all the
way over here
you can see just in the background there
the haunted mansion in the mist it looks
really really cool so let's get this
thing finished so we're going to rack
straight through this because obviously
i actually have a video of how to make
this particular house already on my
channel and
in a weird turn of events i ended up
following my own tutorial somewhat
because i couldn't quite remember all of
the dimensions i did make this several
years ago but while i was there i
thought i could actually make quite a
few improvements to this seeing as
there's some features in minecraft that
have been added that would allow me to
do more however on the inside of this
particular house i created an accidental
mob farm as you can see by the giant
army in there and i was a little bit
surprised to have them continually leave
the haunted mansion
and they just kept coming so i had to
sort of rush in try and light it up it
was a whole thing eventually with the
help of stress who turned up at the last
second thank you stress i was able to
get back to building so one of the big
changes i wanted to make to this wanted
mansion was to make a circular window at
the top and this was possible because of
the introduction of being able to place
trap doors in floating air so i was able
to make some real improvements to the
windows by making the sides a bit
thicker other than that i didn't really
feel the need to change much in the
design i think it's a pretty solid
design and it's actually the haunted
mansion from disneyland paris a pretty
much an exact replica ignore the acacia
wood i just used that because i ran out
of terracotta and then i went ahead and
finished adding all of the other windows
and there we have my haunted mansion
well i think with all those improvements
that i made on the original design this
looks really quite impressive i really i
really really like this design i made
this two or three years ago and i think
it's withstood the test of time for sure
and in the setting of hermit land it
kind of sticks out because it's one of
the only few things that's an actual
building
so oh yeah i really like this but the
actual mini game doesn't quite exist yet
as you can see on the inside it's a
little bit bare bones but the idea of
this whole thing is that the floor is
going to be lava and you're going to
have to jump around the house collecting
stuff so
what you're going to do is you press a
button here
and then you choose a door there might
be one here one here one here and you
jump around avoiding the lava collecting
tokens of some kind you can bail at any
point make your way out the door or you
can dive deeper into the house like
through a crypt or up into the
second floor or even into the roof and
it gets progressively harder as you go
around so you could go around and get 10
tokens then you come here you exchange
your tokens for diamonds which is the
prize but of course it will cost to go
in as well and if you die in the lava
you lose and have to start all over
again i've got a lot of things that i
want to do this episode predominantly i
want to go and finish off the sahara now
thing because i know iska is totally
waiting on me to make the actual
building as for progress on this a
couple of hours building five minutes of
a video i'd say that's really really
decent progress and it's gonna be a fun
mini game when it's done but one of the
other things that i wanted to do is
actually head over here because i've
been seeing falsey
full symmetry making some stuff over
here
says no entry so i'm not going in she's
making like a town over here which is
area 77 alien
alien center so there's clearly
something in the pipeline over here but
what i want to do is actually sneak into
area 77 now and just see if he's hiding
my time machine because i found out
through the comments that it's actually
doc and scar that have built this over
here and what they did was they took my
time machine and villager green who was
inside and they popped it inside the big
hangar that said not to go inside
so
it says no trespassing but
if my if it's in there i kind of want to
there's no one here to stop me he's not
online
i've i don't like this i don't like this
at all
has it always been like this could i
have walked in this entire time
i'm pretty sure it was closed before to
be honest let's just go and get our time
machine back
oh
there's a puffer fish was this meant to
be a trap because
that's a pretty bad trap let's save this
puffer fish otherwise he's gonna he's
gonna struggle was it it ain't it ain't
here and i don't know why i put that an
american accent it ain't here and you'll
never find it
why is there a llama here the time oh
the time machine was taken for
everyone's safety
it ain't here and you will never find it
and villager green's gone as well
assuming that's where
he was this isn't as big as it looks
from the outside i thought i thought
that this would go on for for ages you
know i'm taking this puffer fish
i think this puffer fish was meant to to
hurt me but it didn't do particularly
well if it's not here
then it might be
somewhere else in area 77 because i know
for a fact that there are other
buildings
somewhere
yeah there's some other buildings right
here
there's some like shenanigans going on
over here there's a ravager there's a
wolf oh there we go there's a there's
another building over here are they just
making farms over here
is that what this is they're just making
some farms now there's not even any sign
oh wait no
it's retinol scanner maximum security
clearance required
that's quite a clever use of the
observer block there a retinal scanner
for maximum security
and i guess i guess it's like primed for
either scar or dock now if i'm gonna
break in i'm gonna break in properly i'm
not just gonna walk in i'm gonna do it
properly hold on i know exactly what i
can get
to make this legit because it's scar's
little mini game over here i know for a
fact
he's got everyone's head and if i just
take doc's head
and pop that on
then there's no reason
why i can't get in that little secret
revolt of his there we go it's over here
now probably i could have got in anyway
i could have just mined in with my
pickaxe but you know i'm gonna do it
properly look i got i got doc's head on
so retinol scanner will work is that it
oh yeah it opened sweet
it probably would have worked anyway but
you got to do it properly ow
nice try it ain't here either
dang nabbit
i was so sure it was in here wait a sec
this is like my time machine
configuration two buttons
two buttons uh well this is meant to be
a
clock
and the two yeah two buttons on a lever
okay so what's in here then is there
something inside the portal is this a
trap what is this about
absolutely nothing i really shouldn't
walk into area 77 and just press all the
buttons okay well let's check if there's
any other buildings that it might be in
so we got that one we got these i had a
look in there nothing and there's a
tower over here no nothing under here
oh man
they've totally hidden my time machine
i know what they do
not touch i'm not touching that
okay they've officially hidden my time
machine from me we need to go and put
this dock head back
run out of golden carrots as well i can
just pick some up from my shop
diamonds ahoy
you know i really as good as this
build-off house is it's not very
practical
so i'm thinking what whoa
seriously we've
what is going on here
oh
that can't have anything to do with this
oh wait unless it
totally dropped some sort of explosive
on here
seriously i don't think i can keep up
with this anymore in the space of like
two days my time machine was stolen a
giant mansion was built a town has been
started
and some random how did i not see this
and this
they've just sprung out of nowhere
let's go and have a look up in here as
well there's so many weird things going
on i don't know whose response like
a dokkan scar responsible for this as
well
oh my goodness oh my goodness i thought
i just released a lot of
oh my goodness i thought it might have
just released lots of tnt okay what are
these smooth quartz oh it's just quartz
sweet three quarts
okay i'm officially confused now i have
no idea who made this who made this i
know that fall started this town and i
don't know where my time machine's gone
however what i was trying to say is that
this house while beautiful and is a mark
of the build-off it's not a very
practical house in fact it's so
impractical that my storage i say
storage my mess of shulker boxes has
started overflowing outside so what i'm
thinking is i'm going to make a proper
base over in hermitland hermitville this
area is awesome now i'm going to make a
proper base over towards the town maybe
not in the town itself but i'm going to
make a proper base just outside of area
77 mainly so i can keep an eye on what's
going on here and hopefully i can get my
time machine back
all right well the line over here starts
a bit further away so maybe we can use
this area
this might be better
i can just about see it in the distance
and
there's a few bits i can see like that
building there but this might be a
really good place to set up shop
so now we start a brand new base
but i don't really want to have to build
like a giant mansion or something i
think i might take a leaf out of
folsom's book and make like a camper van
and have like
you know since this is area 77 which is
meant to be like a military installation
maybe we go for like camps and camper
vans and tents and that kind of thing
that style thing
over here
we're in the flower field if we we can
plant more flowers and it will be it'll
be like an anti-government base over
here i don't really like just moving
base for the sake of it but this seems
like a really good opportunity to
improve my hermitville hermit land
experience by having a proper storage
room a bit more space that makes sense
and
to keep an eye on whatever's going on
over here
i'm kind of surprised though how popular
this area has become
since the start of hermitville and it
was just a village that not everyone was
picking up
friend says green you busy my dude no
nah just i did not mean to shout that
nah just building
whoops cats i don't know am i the only
one that reads capitals in
as shouting would you mind helping me
test something at my raceway real quick
raceway
just behind scars cowboy lamb can't miss
it
can't miss it i totally missed it
i was just there a second ago and i
totally missed it
all right let's go and let's go and help
him out i mean that was pretty dull work
but we've laid some groundwork here
actually we probably better leave a sign
that we're going to be working here i
probably put too much detail in that but
greensland do not build going to be
finding my time machine soon but i need
a base and stuff thanks i was actually
just going to say i'm going to be
finding my time machine but it looks
silly just having machine on one side so
i put soon but i need a base and stuff
thanks all right so no one's going to
build there let's head over to ren's
place
wow what the heck
whoa
i love the fact that everyone is making
an awesome mini game is this going to be
for horses oh or boats but boats don't i
mean boats don't go particularly fast on
the stone
it might be a very slow race
but this looks awesome look at the size
of this thing
everyone's making such awesome mini
games ravager run the siege of doom and
then you got some the hide and seek one
then we've got some smaller ones like my
dig straight down and this thing ah
there it is there's ren so oh sorry
sorry my dude i was meant to be helping
right what's up my man yeah not bad i
just saw this thing you said you said
it's behind scars thing can't miss it i
literally flew over and i completely
missed it nice yeah yeah dude this is
massive what do you is it horse race
boat race
it's boat racing it's still under
construction i'm making like a boat race
because everybody loves ice you know so
um it's huge and the thing is i want to
get some redstone in it i kind of want
to like find a way to track how many
laps you do right so i'm doing some
experimenting over here with these
dispensers and i just i've got like my
notebook over here right and i just want
to take some notes and i just need to
see somebody passing over this
area so yeah that's basically like the
mystery box is a mario kart kind of
thing yeah exactly exactly right you're
going to sort of get some elite and
stuff out of it so if you just hop in
the boat and just press forward and um
that's literally all i needed to do
right now so yeah there we go um awesome
yeah that worked perfect thanks dude no
you didn't go back to doing what dude
you can't you can't
you just like yeah
i can't just run away i immediately saw
it went straight into my hand dude what
what went straight into your head
potato dang it dang it you i thought
this through properly
no
you busted me oh man i mean it was a
decent try right right i think it might
have worked if it didn't go i had like
an empty slot and it just went straight
into my hand
oh
dang it
i thought it was so sneaky i was so
proud of what i'd done here but what was
the punishment anyway
plan
yeah it was a spicy one i'm editing it
kaplan you have you have been sputtered
hot potatoed here is your punishment for
your next episode you must wear tomato
yoshi's skin for the entire episode and
become the sensei i will send this skin
via discord ren you do realize you've
got to do this now
what yeah the rules of hot potato is if
you're caught sending the hot potato the
punishment backfires no so you've got to
do a punishment
oh
this is what happens when you go on
holiday i i didn't actually know that
did you know the rules effort into this
if i knew that
no
well look you're gonna become tomato i'm
so glad that i saw this now i would i do
not want to wear that skin in fact go
and put it on right now i want to see it
okay hello young one no no
no red
uh yeah so you've got to wear that for
your next episode now because this
punishment has officially backfired and
i think
yeah you can't i don't think you can
give your next target i mean you can try
and get me again but it's just gonna
backfire because you know yeah
i mean you know now so i'm gonna have i
know you i didn't even know you had the
potato i thought stress had it yeah oh
well there's only one other hermit
online it's a zuma he's looks like he's
afk his camera count is an afk but he's
afk i think he might have he might have
like a clicker on or something
we should go and check afk target is is
going to be much easier dude you want to
help me out with this one oh dude
i'm always down to help someone get
potatoes but we've got to come up with a
really good punishment
sweet azuba we're covered for you bro
please take that skin off though
please go back
one episode is enough
beep
yeah x is definitely fk so if we go and
check his base first
and then we'll see if he's we've got to
find him first that's the problem he
could be at one of like a million bases
i've devised a new punishment by the way
for x's next episode
he's gonna have to switch his w and s
keybinds
oh so every time he walks forward he's
walking backwards every time yeah the
whole episode
well wait hang on uh ten minutes ten
minutes okay
yeah it's gonna say the whole episode's
maybe a little bit harsh yeah all right
let's see if yeah it's pretty spice okay
okay uh yeah this is his base hopefully
he's in here
you know what
i think i've only ever been in here once
it's kind of
spooky
yeah
very spooky what is the afk here
well it's usually like right in the
middle here because it triggers all of
his guardian spawns and whatnot um
yeah don't see any name tag and stuff
either so
um let's check one of his other farms
come run we must go into the boat
onward
um this might be a farm let's check this
one might be might be
i think most of his farms are here do
not it says do not enter oh okay
uh
i mean if a sign says do not enter with
entering right so
yeah this is another one of his farms
okay uh where would you afk here
i guess all the way at the top there
it's like an observer platform
i think that's probably the spawning
platform then they'll come down here and
he'd oh yeah here it's totally here
yeah he's not here he's he's not right
okay next one get out of here yeah i
mean he probably kept them on the same
line so they were close and easy to get
to yeah there's another pool so
ooh okay
let's go for it he's still afk
excellent
um
i've been in this room i have no idea
where to go
where's the spoiler up there
the actual farm is here that looks like
the mechanics
oh bubble baiter
oh dude he's totally here
oh
oh okay okay okay perfect perfect okay
i've got the spud if we make minecraft
sounds he might come back
okay
i don't know how quiet
you could put it you could straight is
in his inventory or
if he stuff's in that chest you could
pop it in one of his shulker boxes to
guarantee that he's going to pick it up
or you could just pop it in his
inventory
um it's going to show up in his hands
though right i guess because he's got
nothing on i think if he hears the chest
he's going to hear the pop right well
maybe okay
up to you do you want to put it in a
shulker box here we go dude this is it
totally missed there we go we got it
potato potato
boop nice nice
get outta here is he gonna find you
don't stop it scarf
get out of here man
no don't
[Laughter]
i think you can call that a proper
potato wing
yes
victory
get potato deceiver
we could we could go back and dispense
some stuff on him as well we gotta let
him know who is responsible yes
we'll put i've got some cursive binding
books we've got your head so i'll give
you the dispenser and the lever that's
for you
i'm gonna put i'm gonna enchant the this
armor there we go we got tubular
trousers
yeah boots
and the potato shirt of shame
love it
i've got the dispenser and the lever
now we just got to get it on his body
beautiful all right we gotta we gotta
risk it again let's go back okay here we
go okay
um
all right here we go
i zoomer
he's adorable isn't he look at him all
of his stuff's in here
oh you couldn't have done the shulker
box thing anyway isn't going any shelter
boxes there
okay here we go dispenser
first
the ren head boom oh he's looking
amazing look at that really brings out
his eyes oh beautiful
let's put the trousers on
kirsten finding oh this is so good dude
this is you know this just makes this
victory so much sweeter you know
it really does it just it's absolutely
gorgeous um what else do we need the
boots the boots there we go perfect and
now we skedaddle out of here
that's beautiful
gg is sigma get right
by enjoy your potato
[Music]
green this is the sweetest victory i've
ever experienced thanks my dude no you
said it back up that's exactly what
happened to me well now that we've been
thoroughly distracted by rendog's potato
shenanigans i can get back to what i was
doing which is trying to make myself
a rv or a caravan i'm not sure i have
never made one of these before as far as
i'm aware but i know the theory which is
basically what i'm doing now a bunch of
quartz slabs i've got uh some wheels
here and this is going to be my base now
obviously
this is not going to be where i store
everything in fact i'm hoping to hide a
way down in the middle of this to an
underground base because what's going to
be up here is just a front but we'll get
to that another episode i want to make
this place look really legit we got the
beginnings of a fire pit going on here
but i'm actually running out of the
different kinds of blocks i need for
this so yeah we're gonna have a central
fire pit and then we have our rv here
and i can even make it look like it just
got parked by having some tracks like
that
i think it might be easier just to start
with a shell and then remove the bits
that i need later on to make the shape
so i'll just start by making the actual
box the shape that it needs to
be actually this is normal quartz you
see the grid pattern here if i actually
change this for smooth quartz
you remove that grid pattern altogether
which will make this look
well less like tetris anyway so we're
gonna have to repair all that and change
this up
sometimes it doesn't matter how long
you've been playing minecraft you've
still got to google stuff
it turns out to get this into smooth
quartz i need i needed to put it in a
furnace
which yeah i didn't really think of
it's all the little details you can put
in that matter for this one
it looks a lot more like a truck than an
rv if you ask me something's not right
here
i think the issue is that we need to put
like a strip of color into it i think
that's that's the main thing because all
of these rvs have like this strip that
runs all the way that is immediately
looking better
this is a lot more challenging than i
thought it was going to be but i think
it's going to come out rather well
i'm trying to figure out what's wrong
with this rv but it's it's honestly
getting the better of me i might need to
go and look for some inspiration here
and look at maybe some real uh images of
some recreational vehicles maybe it's
just too short maybe i need to actually
make it a bit longer i think it also
needs the bit the tarpool that goes over
the edge but maybe i made it just too
big as well maybe it's just a bit out of
scale might be one block too high in
fact
it may just be one block too high
because it looks like a bus at the
moment i think that is actually the
issue however
i'm afraid we have actually run out of
time for this episode of hermitcraft i
didn't even get most of the stuff that i
wanted to get done today at all but
there is something that i need to ask
you guys for your help
so i'm pre-recording a little bit
because i'm going away
and i actually need your help i wanted
to do another episode of a series i did
quite a long time ago called building
your comments
but the comments from those old videos
they're kind of outdated so
if you want to contribute all you have
to do is comment in the comments down
below and say byc
that's build your comments and then say
what you want me to build in the
building your comments world man that's
a that's a lot of me saying comments but
hopefully that makes sense so for
example byc
make green making an rv
which still doesn't look quite right oh
my goodness this is a nightmare absolute
nightmare i'm going to mess around with
this design until i get it right but if
you want to contribute comment down
below byc and then your idea for a
building your comments video other than
that thank you very much for watching
everyone i hope you enjoyed this episode
hopefully next episode this rv will be
up and running and also
i will start on the actual mini game
inside the floor is lava and hopefully i
will have made sahara now lots of things
to do including
remembering how to build one of these
very annoying thank you very much for
watching and good bye